HARUNA SALAMI

samlak1999@gmail.com | devsamlak.netlify.app | linkedin.com/in/devsamlak

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Seasoned software engineer with over 5 years of experience, specializing in frontend engineering and building AI applications. Built Penmaniacs from scratch and grew it into thousands of users. Helped Venngage onboard 500,000 users by redesigning their platform.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PENMANIACS December 2022 – Present

Penmaniacs is an AI educational assistant that helps students learn, study and write faster.

Co-Founder (Software Engineer)

- Ideated, designed and built the project from scratch to thousands of users.
- Built and integrated a design system that makes it 40% faster to build new components or pages.
- Wrote the prompt that instructed the AI model to generate human-like academic content.
- Helped to optimize the pricing and the pricing page which led to a 100% increase in revenue.

VENNGAGE, Canada.

May 2021 – March 2023

Venngage is a simple infographics tool that enables people to create beautiful infographics in a minute.

Software Engineer

- Works with the marketing team in redesigning the platform to increase traffic and make it user-friendly.
- Developed various accessibility tool that makes it easier for users to make an accessible design that is WCAG compliant. Making it the go-to platform for accessible design.
- This helped to increase the traffic to 24 million visits and about 500,000 users were onboarded.

CLOUT WALLET, United States.

April 2021

Clout Wallet is a crypto portfolio management platform built on top of Bitclout.

Software Engineer

- Built the portfolio dashboard that makes it easier for users to track their Bitclout investments.
- I aggregated the user's investments by connecting to the Bitclout protocol through their SDK.

FREEUP, United States.

December 2020 – March, 2021

FreeUp is a marketplace for connecting business owners with talented freelancers from all over the world.

Freelance Web Developer

• Wrote a script for a data-driven company in the United Kingdom to scrape over 20 thousand products from top UK e-commerce websites.

EDUCATION

FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY, AKURE

2015 - 2021

Bachelor of Technology

SKILLS

Language: HTML, CSS, Javascript and Typescript

Technology: React JS, Next JS, Node JS, Redux, MongoDB, Git, Prompt Engineering, Tailwind CSS, Styled

Components, Jest

Interest: Teaching (introduced 70 students to programming), Reading and Travelling.